Guide to the Abraham Epstein Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Contents List
  - N.Y. (State): (Box 38)
    - Legislative Hearing Conference--Correspondence, lists, etc. (January 1938-May 1929) in 2 Folders. (Box 38)
    - Meetings, & conferences--Correspondence, (March 1929-February 1930) (Box 38)
    - Repeal attempts--Correspondence, etc. (December 1931-April 1932) (Box 38)
    - N.Y.: (Box 38)
    - Albany--Correspondence, (June 1929-February 1942) in 2 Folders. (Box 38)
    - Hearing--Bil1 for old age security--Correspondence, lists, etc. (January 1930-February 1931) in 2 Folders. (Box 38)
    - Albany Conference on Old Age Security--Correspondence, remarks, lists (October 1932) (Box 38)
    - Andrews, Elmer F., Dept. of Labor--Correspondence, (September’35-November'38) (Box 38)
    - Binghamptor--Correspondence, (October 1929-0ct. 1932) (Box 38)
    - Buffalo--Correspondence, (June 1929-March 1921) (Box 39)
    - Dept. of Social Welfare--Correspondence, (February 1934-October 1941), etc. (Box 39)
    - Dept. of Social We1fare. Schneider, David M. One thousand recipients of old age allowances (1935) (Box 39)
    - Joint Legislative Welfare Com., etc.--Corres., etc. (February 1928-Ju1y 1929) (Box 39)
    - N.Y. Commission on Old Age Security--Correspondence, (April 1929-February 1933) (Box 39)
    - N.Y. Constitutional Convention. Com. on Social Welfare. (Box 39)
    - NY. Edward Corsi--Correspondence, (July-Aug, 1938) (Box 39)
  - Permanent Conference on Old Age Security: (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, releases, lists, speeches, minutes, etc. (January 1927-May 1934) in 7 Folders. (Box 40)
  - N.Y.: (Box 41)
    - Permanent Conference-Correspondence, minutes.. etc. (January ‘37-November ‘41) in 2 Folders. (Box 41)
    - Permanent Conference. Com. on Education--Correspondence, minutes, etc. (January 1934-April 1935) (Box 41)
    - Permanent Conference. Executive Com. affiliated organizations--Correspondence, etc. (September 1929-June 1937) in 3 Folders. (Box 41)
    - Rochester--Correspondence, (July 1929-February 1942) (Box 42)
    - Roosevelt, F.D., 1929-33 3 letters (photocopied) (Box 42)
    - Senate: (Box 42)
    - Byrne, William T.--Correspondence, (December 1934-January 1936) (Box 42)
    - Mautick, Seabury C. & Mastick bill--Correspondence, etc. (January 1930-January 1934) (Box 42)
    - Mandelbaum, Samue1-- Correspondence an act (January 1933-January 1936) (Box 42)
    - Syracuse--Correspondence, (October 1929-May 1936) (Box 42)
    - Utica--Correspondence, (July.1929-October 1935) (Box 42)
  - New Zealand--Pamphlets, Correspondence, annual reports., forms, etc. (1908-January 1927) (Box 42)
  - Nordholm, Alex--Correspondence, (September 1935-July 1938) (Box 42)
  - North Carolina--Correspondence, Public welfare progress (January 1930-April 1938) (Box 42)
  - North Dakota--Correspondence, (May 1930-March 1936) (Box 42)
  - Ohio: (Box 43)
    - Bills, statistics, conferences, Correspondence, lists, etc. (December 1930-December 1931) (Box 43)
    - Old Age Security herald (July-August 1931) (Box 43)
    - Correspondence, (April 1928-March 1941) (Box 43)
    - Old Age refund--Correspondence, (September 1939-Apri 1940) (Box 43)
    - Old Age Pensions & Unemployment Campaign (1929-1938) (photocopies) (Box 43)
    - Bigelow, Herbert S.--Correspondence, etc. (February 1928-March 1937) (Box 43)
    - Cincinnati--Correspondence, (November 1928-July 1941) (Box 43)
    - Columbus--Correspondence, (January 1929-April 1942) (Box 43)
    - Cleveland--Correspondence, (January 1937-December 1941), Rose leaves (June '41) (Box 43)
    - Dayton--Correspondence, (September 1929-February 1939) (Box 43)
    - Toledo--Correspondence, (February 1931-April 1937) (Box 43)
  - Oklahoma. Old Age Pension Bill--Correspondence etc. (April 1928-November 1932);(March 1933-(October 1939) (Box 44)
  - Old age pensions--Development, foreign countries, etc..--Articles, lists, etc. (1916-February 1929) (Box 44)
  - Old age pensions--Development in various states & so on--Articles, etc. (1908-February 1929) (Box 44)
  - Old age pensions--N.Y., Ky., etc.--Correspondence, (January 1934-August 1943) in 2 Folders. (Box 44)
  - Old age pensions--Schemes (June 1929 etc.) (Box 44)
  - Old Folks’ Relief Society, Inc... NY. City--Correspondence, (May 1930-December 1934) (Box 44)
  - Oppositions to old age pensions--Articles & general data, clippings, letters, etc. (April 1931-July 1933) (Box 45)
  - Oregon--Correspondence, etc. (January 1928-July 1940) (Box 45)
  - Organizations--Reports, Correspondence, resolutions (September 1927-February 1934) (Box 45)
  - Organizations, etc. endorsing old age pensions--Pamphlets, etc. (December ‘28) (Box 45)
  - Organizations magazines, etc.--Correspondence, (October 1927-December 1928); (January 1929-May 1930) (Box 45)
  - Pennsylvania--Correspondence, (December 1926-December 1929) in 2 Folders. (Box 46)
  - Pennsylvania--Correspondence, (January 1937-July 1942) (Box 46)
  - PA:
    - Allentown--Com. & general correspondence, etc. (November 1931-October 1941) (Box 46)
    - Altoona--Com. & general corres., etc. (December 1931-November 1934) (Box 46)
    - Chamber of Commerce--Bul., lists, correspondence, etc. (May-December 1926) (Box 46)
    - Chamber of Commerce--Pa. progress, monthly (July 1926-September 1928) (Box 46)
    - Com. On Old Age Security--Corres., etc. (December 1931.-January 1954) (Box 46)
    - Federation (Box 46)
    - Easton--Com. & general correspondence, etc. (November 1931-April 1934) (Box 46)
    - Erie—Com. & general correspondence, etc. (November 1931-1932) (Box 46)
    - Federation of Labor: (Box 46)
    - Reports, resolutions, etc. (May ‘24-'28) (Box 46)
    - Maurer, James Hudson .Correspondence, etc. (Box 46)
    - Maurer, James Hudson .Correspondence, etc. (January 1928-April 1942) (Box 46)
    - Fight--Correspondence, acts, supreme court records, etc. (May ‘32-November'33) (Box 47)
    - Ford City. Almshouse, etc.--Re-inspect1on sheets, articles, etc. (February 1922-October 1923) (Box 47)
    - Harrisburg--Correspondence. (May 1936-April 1942) (Box 47)
    - Pittsburgh--Correspondence, (February 1936-April 1942) (Box 47)
    - Reading--Correspondence, etc. (April 1931-February 1933) (Box 47)
    - Scranton--Correspondence, etc. (March 1932-December 1932) (Box 47)
    - Wilkes-Barre--Correspondence, etc. (February 1933-June 1939) (Box 47)
    - Senate. Vare. Old Age Pension Amendment--Fight-Correspondence, reports, etc. (April 1924-April 1927) in 2 Folders. (Box 47)
    - Old Age Assistance Commission--Articles & Miscellaneous data (1924-1927) in 2 Folders. (Box 47)
    - Old Age Pension Commission--Correspondence, certificate, etc. (May 1924-May 1927) (Box 47)
    - Security League. Schermerhorn, Gertrude L.--Correspondence, newsletters, etc. (August 1934-July 1936) (Box 47)
  - People’s Lobby, Wash, D.C. --Correspondence, declaration, etc. (December ‘29-November ‘39) (Box 48)
  - Personal Correspondence, (January 1924-February 1937) in 3 fo1ders. (Box 48)
  - Philadelphia--Correspondence, (1937-1941) (Box 48)
  - Philadelphia Conference--Correspondence, lists, etc. (May-November 1930) (Box 48)
  - Policyholders' Advisory Council--Correspondence, constitution, testimony (April-September 1939) (Box 48)
  - Pope, Willard, Detroit, Mich.--Correspondence, etc. (May 1930-0ct. 1938) (Box 48)
  - Portugal--Decreto n.5 (mai 1919) (Box 48)
  - Principles, Statement of, an article ?F1ynn (February 1938-May 1940) (Box 48)
  - Rackets: (Box 49)
    - Health--Clippings (February-June 1934) (Box 49)
    - Old age pensions--"National Old Age Pension Assn." by "Dr." J.E.Pope--Clippings, Correspondence, etc. (1933-1936) in 2 Folders. (Box 49)
    - Old age pensions--Townsend Clubs, San Diego, Calif.-Correspondence, etc. (February 1933-February 1936) in 3 Folders. (Box 49)
    - Social security--Miscellaneous correspondence, clippings, etc. (July 1933-October 1941) in 2 Folders. (Box 49)
  - Railroad Retirement Board. Latimore, Murray W.--Correspondence, (May '35-November'40) (Box 50)
  - Reed, Dr. Louis S., Md.--Correspondence, (December 1937-Jan 1941) (Box 50)
  - Reporting service (stenotype)--Corres. (July 1930-February 1941) (Box 50)
  - Republican Program Com. (Glenn Frank)--Correspondence, program, charges, etc. (March 1937-January 1942) (Box 50)
  - Rhode Island:
    - Correspondence, (December 1933-November 1941) (Box 50)
    - Council for Old Age Security--Correspondence, (September 1930-May 1934) in 2 Folders (Box 50)
    - Minutes (November 1930-February 1932) (Box 50)
    - House. Soriere, Albert A.--Correspondence, (December 1935-February 1937) (Box 50)
  - Roosevelt, pres. Franklin D.:
    - Correspondence, etc. (December 1928-September 1940) (Box 50)
    - Clippings (February-July 1934) (Box 50)
  - Rosenberg controversy--Correspondence, press -releases, etc. (September ' 37-July '41) (Box 51)
  - Rosenwald, Julius--Requesting contribution--Correspondence, (November ‘27-January '29) (Box 51)
  - Romania--Act (January 1912), Monitorul oficial (November 1924) (Box 51)
  - Rubinov, Dr. Isaac Max--Correspondence, clippings, etc. (January 1928-January 1939) (Box 51)
  - Sanford, Frederick, N.J. League of Women Voter~-General correspondence (May 1930-February 1931) (Box 52)
  - Sanford, Raymond, Ill. Com. for Old Age Security--Correspondence, (March 1932-October 1935) in 2 Folders. (Box 52)
  - Saposs, David J .--Correspondence, (February 1939-March 1942) (Box 52)
  - Snyderman, George S., Pa.--Correspondence, (February 1933-July 1940) (Box 52)
  - Social Science Research Council—Correspondence (April ’36-November ’40) (Box 52)
  - Social Security Board (Correspondence on the origin of the name "Social Security") (Box 52)
  - South Carolina--Correspondence, (September 1950-August 1938) (Box 52)
  - South Dakota--Correspondence, (February 1934-March 1939) (Box 52)
  - State Com.'s Stationery--Samples (Box 52)
  - Stewart, Bryce M., Industrial Relations Counselors-Suggested changes for H.R. 7260 (April 1935-January 1940) (Box 52)
  - Sweden, Netherlands, Greece--Acts, order, etc. (May '18-August '25) (Box 52)
  - Tennessee--Correspondence, (February 1950-March 1941) (Box 53)
  - Texas--Correspondence, (January 1930-March 1940) (Box 53)
  - Twentieth Century Fund, Inc., Boston--Corres concerning a grant (January 1928-April 1929) (Box 53)
  - Utah--Correspondence, etc.(October 1929-February 1955) (Box 53)
  - Utopian state--Townsend, Dr. E.'s Utopian Society in Southern Calito Utah; Sinclair, Upton.--C1ippings, etc. (December 1931-Sept 1934) (Box 53)
  - Unions--Correspondence, & pamphlets, etc. (1923) (Box 53)
  - United Mine Workers of America. Old Age Pension Commission-Corres. (October-November 1924) (Box 53)
  - U.S. Congress: (Box 54)
    - Amendments to social security act--Correspondence, (December'38-Marcn'39) (Box 54)
    - Congressional Intelligence--Receipt of $25 (September 1935) (Box 54)
    - Dinner on old age pensions, January 1932 (Box 54)
    - Correspondence, lists (December 1931-April 1932) (Box 54)
    - Dinner, March 1934--Correspondence, lists (February-March 1934) (Box 54)
    - House:
      - Ellenbogen, Henry-- Correspondence. (January 1933-November 1938) (Box 54)
      - Fitzgerald, Roy G.--Correspondence, (December 1929-Nay 1930) (Box 54)
    - Senate:
      - Hearings--Correspondence, etc. (December ‘29-January '31) in 2 Folders (Box 54)
      - Hearings--Persons promised to attend--Correspondence, (May '3O) (Box 54)
      - Hearings--Persons unable to attend--Correspondence, (May ‘30) (Box 54)
      - Hearings-on Dill's Old Pension bill, February 1930 (Box 54)
      - Correspondence, etc. (December 1929-March 1931) (Box 54)
      - Budlong, Percy E., Official Reporter--Correspondence, (September-December 1932) (Box 54)
      - Dill, C.C.--Correspondence, bill, etc. (May ‘29-March '43) (Box 54)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor. Lubin, Dr. Isador--Correspondence, (June '33-March '36) (Box 55)
  - Employment Office. Ringe, Helen H.--Correspondence, etc. (September '33-December 35) (Box 55)
  - Social Security Board--Travel orders, contract, correspondence, etc. (October 1939-January 1942) (Box 55)
  - Uruguay--Social legislation, Legislation obrera (October 1919) (Box 55)
  - Vermont--Corres. (November 1932-February 1942) (Box 55)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison--Correspondence, (July 1931-April 1932) (Box 55)
  - Vinton, Warren Jay--Corresp (December 1931-July. 1941) (Box 55)
  - Virginia--Correspondence, (April 1929-September 1942) (Box 55)
  - Va. Senate. Morris, Emma--Correspondence, a bill (May 1930-June 1934) (Box 55)
  - Walter, Dr. Josephine's will--Correspondence, receipt by A.A.S.S., etc. (May 1935-June 1935) (Box 56)
  - Washington--Correspondence, (April 1938-November 1940) (Box 56)
  - Wash.,D.C.:
    - Correspondence, (February l939-May 1942) (Box 56)
    - Memorandum, bill, etc. (Box 56)
    - Conference--Correspondence, (May 1929) (Box 56)
    - Permanent Com. --Minutes, Correspondence, etc. (May 1932-January 1934) (Box 56)
  - West Virginia--Correspondence, (January 1929-May 1940) (Box 56)
  - Whitney, William C.: Foundation. Bogue, Anna--Correspondence, (December 1927-June 1941) in 2 fo1ders (Box 56)
  - Wisconsin--Correspondence, etc. (January 1936-February 1942) (Box 56)
  - Old age pensions law--Pamphlets, Correspondence (June '26-February '28) (Box 56)
  - Workers' Education--Correspondence, (February-May 1941) (Box 56)
  - Workmen's Circle--correspondence, etc. (December 1934-March 1938) (Box 56)
  - Wyoming--Correspondence, etc. (November 1929-Ju1y 1934) (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, I-IV (Box 57-60)
  - Requests for "Negro Migrant" (1918-1921) (Box 61)
  - American Assn. for Social Security--Clippings (1930) (Box 62)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, I-IV (Box 63-66)
  - Electrictype cuts reprints--Scrapbook (Box 67)
  - Editorials--Scrapbook (1932-1933) (Box 68)
  - Magazine articles--Scrapbook (1919-1930) (Box 69)
  - Miscellaneous scrapbooks (Box 70-73)
  - Lecture material, New York University (Box 74)
  - "Insecurity: A Challenge to America": Typescript (Box 75-78)
  - "Challenge of the Aged": typescript with related materials (Box 79)
  - Old Age Pensions (Box 80)
  - Misc. manuscripts; Misc. newspaper clippings, including letters to the editor of N.Y. Times from A. & H.C. Epstein and some pamphlets (Gift 1978) (Box 81)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 82-84)
  - American Association for Social Security: Membership Cards (Box 85-86)
  - Photographs (Box 46)